<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Solar on Sustainable Community Development Hub</title>
    <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/solar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Solar on Sustainable Community Development Hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/solar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DC Microgrid Product Review</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2018/04/dc-microgrid-product-review/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2018/04/dc-microgrid-product-review/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DGqp5eTHxUY Specialized Solar Systems Published on Oct 26, 2013   SYSTEM BACKGROUND The SS20 is Specialized Solar Systems(SSS) most commonly supplied off-grid solar DC microgrid baseline smartbox systems and has many applications. It can be used where grid electrification is not available and also to supplement it. It generates enough power to provide adequate lighting, entertainment and also can power a fridge or a freezer (View the brochure). The initial system supplied consists of three interior lights that can be used for eight hours a night, one exterior security light, a 75W panel, a 102AH battery, stainless steel battery box all necessary cable and a solar panel roof- or floor-mount bracket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deng Ltd, Ghana, Solar electricity for rural communities - Ashden Award winner</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/deng-ltd-ghana-solar-electricity-for-rural-communities-ashden-award-winner/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/deng-ltd-ghana-solar-electricity-for-rural-communities-ashden-award-winner/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y7jzJ0jIzmE
Deng Ltd, an established engineering company in Accra, has developed a viable and sustainable business model for the provision of solar-home-systems to rural areas where access to grid electricity is limited. Deng has done this by venturing out of the capital and setting up a network of dealers to service the more remote areas. Deng has also set up a training centre for solar technicians in order to further expand the business and ensure the future sustainability of the scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramble On- Colorado State University Hosts One of Largest Solar Plants at a U.S. University</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/ramble-on-colorado-state-university-hosts-one-of-largest-solar-plants-at-a-u-s-university/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/ramble-on-colorado-state-university-hosts-one-of-largest-solar-plants-at-a-u-s-university/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9HbgzSNeJGA
Did you know that Colorado State University is home to one of the largest solar plants at a U.S. university? The plant, located on the Foothills Campus (west&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shidhulai Swanirvar Sangstha, Bangladesh, solar pv boats - Ashden Award winner</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/shidhulai-swanirvar-sangstha-bangladesh-solar-pv-boats-ashden-award-winner-2/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/shidhulai-swanirvar-sangstha-bangladesh-solar-pv-boats-ashden-award-winner-2/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f6IVgV_rsU0
Shidhulai Swanirvar Sangstha was founded in 1998 to help poor, marginalised communities living in the remote Chalanbeel region of Bangladesh to develop sustainable livelihoods. Shidhulai has achieved this by building up a fleet of flat-bottomed boats, all made with locally available materials, that make their way through the shallow rivers and canals of the Chalanbeel to bring a range of educational services and renewable energy supplies to water-side families. The boats use solar PV modules to generate all the electricity they need to provide daily classes in primary education for children, libraries, training in sustainable agriculture, health advice, mobile phone and internet access and battery-charging facilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solarcentury, UK, Solar PV power for homes and businesses - Ashden Award winner</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/solarcentury-uk-solar-pv-power-for-homes-and-businesses-ashden-award-winner/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/solarcentury-uk-solar-pv-power-for-homes-and-businesses-ashden-award-winner/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k_yo1wOvFks
This video can be downloaded here: http://www.ashdenawards.org/winners/solarcentury Solarcentury won an Ashden Award for Sustainable Energy in 2007.
Solarcentury is a beacon for the UK&amp;rsquo;s solar power market, showing how attractive, flexible and easy to install solar PV can be, even in crowded urban areas. The company has used innovative design to develop a range of excellent solar products &amp;ndash; mainly solar PV panels and some solar water heating &amp;ndash; and mounting systems to fit a wide range of buildings, including industrial estates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Environment Day- Africa Sustainable Energy</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/world-environment-day-africa-sustainable-energy/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/world-environment-day-africa-sustainable-energy/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1-NhA2FCHrU
Uploaded on Jun 5, 2009 In Africa, UNDP, as an implementing partner of the Global Environment Facility (GEF), is getting people in remote areas onto the electrical grid by harnessing green sources of energy like hydropower and solar energy. In the Embu district of central Kenya, a high rate of rainfall combined with a large amount of runoff water from the snows of Mount Kenya made hydropower the obvious choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zara Solar Ltd, Tanzania, Affordable rural solar pv energy - Ashden Award winner</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/zara-solar-ltd-tanzania-affordable-rural-solar-pv-energy-ashden-award-winner/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/zara-solar-ltd-tanzania-affordable-rural-solar-pv-energy-ashden-award-winner/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SHgXR2cmVyA
Uploaded on Feb 26, 2008 This video can be downloaded here: http://www.ashdenawards.org/winners/zara Zara Solar won an Ashden Award for Sustainable Energy in 2007.
You can follow us on: Facebook http://bit.ly/9GKbIM Twitter http://twitter.com/AshdenAwards Blog: http://www.ashdenawards.org/blog/latest
To find out more visit the link above and check out the Ashden Awards Blog http://ashdenawards.blogspot.com
Zara Solar Ltd. is the leading provider of solar PV in Northern Tanzania. Given that only 10% of the whole population and 2% of the rural population have access to the electricity grid in Tanzania, solar energy would seem to be an obvious alternative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zara Solar Ltd, Tanzania, Affordable rural solar pv energy - Ashden Award winner</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/zara-solar-ltd-tanzania-affordable-rural-solar-pv-energy-ashden-award-winner/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/zara-solar-ltd-tanzania-affordable-rural-solar-pv-energy-ashden-award-winner/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SHgXR2cmVyA
Uploaded on Feb 26, 2008 This video can be downloaded here: http://www.ashdenawards.org/winners/zara Zara Solar won an Ashden Award for Sustainable Energy in 2007.
You can follow us on: Facebook http://bit.ly/9GKbIM Twitter http://twitter.com/AshdenAwards Blog: http://www.ashdenawards.org/blog/latest
To find out more visit the link above and check out the Ashden Awards Blog http://ashdenawards.blogspot.com
Zara Solar Ltd. is the leading provider of solar PV in Northern Tanzania. Given that only 10% of the whole population and 2% of the rural population have access to the electricity grid in Tanzania, solar energy would seem to be an obvious alternative.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>