<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conservation Solutions Afrika on Sustainable Community Development Hub</title>
    <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/conservation-solutions-afrika/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conservation Solutions Afrika on Sustainable Community Development Hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/conservation-solutions-afrika/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mordecai Ogada, Director of Conservation Solutions Afrika – The Big Conservation Lie</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/08/the-big-conservation-lie/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/08/the-big-conservation-lie/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GmeNvyNYQTo
&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s the difference between bush meat and game meat? Its usually the skin color of the person consuming it..&amp;rdquo; - Mordecai Ogada
https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=551&amp;amp;v=3_YuC29wS0c
Presenting on his new book The Big Conservation Lie. Sponsored by CSU SOGES Africa Center and The Department of Human Dimensions of Natural Resources, Warner College of Natural Resources, Colorado State University.
Department of Human Dimensions of Natural Resources
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_fzackQy7dM
Hukka Wario 4 months ago This book, The Big Conservation Lie, by Mbaria and Ogada is a must read for all who respect traditional and indigenous pastoralist peoples living in harmony with nature and with wildlife, and who have a reason to look with distrust and suspicion at the new white self proclaimed apostles of wildlife conservation, who have established rangeland trusts financed by western capital and displacing, peripheralizing and marginalizing pastoral peoples branding then invaders, bandits, poachers and even terrorists in their own ancestral lands.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>