<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Climate on Sustainable Community Development Hub</title>
    <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/tag/climate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Climate on Sustainable Community Development Hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://scdhub.netlify.com/tag/climate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>earth.nullschool.net</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2018/04/earth-nullschool-net/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2018/04/earth-nullschool-net/index.html/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
earth.nullschool.net URL path allows simple queries of past events &amp;amp; climate conditions.
a visualization of global weather conditions forecast by supercomputers updated every three hours
ocean surface current estimates updated every five days
ocean surface temperatures and anomaly from daily average (1981-2011) updated daily
ocean waves updated every three hours
aurora updated every thirty minutes
 &amp;nbsp;    Wind wind speed at specified height   Temp temperature at specified height   RH relative humidity at specified height   WPD Instantaneous Wind Power Density measure of power available in the wind: ½ρv3, where ρ is air density and v is wind velocity   TPW Total Precipitable Water total amount of water in a column of air stretching from ground to space   TCW Total Cloud Water total amount of water in clouds in a column of air from ground to space   3HPA 3-hour Precipitation Accumulation amount of precipitation over the next three hours   CAPE Convective Available Potential Energy from Surface indicates the buoyancy of air, a measure of atmospheric instability and predictor of severe weather   MSLP Mean Sea Level Pressure air pressure reduced to sea level   MI Misery Index perceived air temperature as combination of heat index and wind chill   SST Sea Surface Temperature temperature of the ocean surface   SSTA Sea Surface Temperature Anomaly difference in ocean temperature from daily average during years 1981-2011   HTSGW Significant Wave Height roughly equal to mean wave height as estimated by a &amp;ldquo;trained observer&amp;rdquo;   COsc Carbon Monoxide Surface Concentration the fraction of carbon monoxide present in air at the earth&amp;rsquo;s surface   CO2sc Carbon Dioxide Surface Concentration the fraction of carbon dioxide present in air at the earth&amp;rsquo;s surface   SO2sm Sulfur Dioxide Surface Mass amount of sulfur dioxide in the air near the earth&amp;rsquo;s surface   DUex Dust Extinction the aerosol optical thickness (AOT) of light at 550 nm due to dust   SO4ex Sulfate Extinction the aerosol optical thickness (AOT) of light at 550 nm due to sulfate   PM1 Particulate Matter &amp;lt; 1 µm mass of atmospheric particles with a diameter less than 1 micron   PM2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making sense of disaster situation reports</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/09/making-sense-of-disaster-situation-reports/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/09/making-sense-of-disaster-situation-reports/index.html/</guid>
      <description>This is a good reference for what to look for in a good situation report.
https://www.humanityroad.org/situation-reports/caribbean/hurricane-maria</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soneva Kiri Coral Garden 15 Months After Installation</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/07/soneva-kiri-coral-garden-15-months-after-installation/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/07/soneva-kiri-coral-garden-15-months-after-installation/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H9p5U4M7bhw
The Soneva Kiri Coral Garden was set up by Coral Reef Creator&amp;rsquo;s Team in Koh Kood - Thailand in October 2011. About 2000 coral fragments where grafted on this news coral reef ecosystem. This movie was released in January 2013. You can see the result 15 months after coral transplantation.
This is a useful video for its identification of common coral reef fish species as well.
The song played with the video gets an A rating as well, seeming to create its own meditative dancey coral reef restoration music genre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate change and food</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/climate-change-and-food/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/climate-change-and-food/index.html/</guid>
      <description>In part three of our series on climate change and health we examine how environmental changes will affect not only the food we can grow, but how they will make what we&amp;rsquo;re already growing less nutritious.
https://soundcloud.com/harvardpublichealth/march-2-2017-climate-change-and-food?in=harvardpublichealth/sets/harvard-chan-this-week-in</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clemson EWB- New Orleans Trip Nov. 3-7, 2006</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/02/clemson-ewb-new-orleans-trip-nov-3-7-2006/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/02/clemson-ewb-new-orleans-trip-nov-3-7-2006/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DW0G90u7QB8
During Fall Break, members of Clemson University&amp;rsquo;s chapter of Engineers Without Borders traveled to New Orleans to help with cleanup efforts there. This video shows pictures taken while we were gutting a house for an elderly woman, Ms. Audrey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate change the state of the science (data visualization)</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/climate-change-the-state-of-the-science-data-visualization/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/climate-change-the-state-of-the-science-data-visualization/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_EWOrZQ3L-c
Published on 19 Nov 2013 Produced by the International Geosphere-Biosphere Programme and Globaia and funded by the UN Foundation.
The data visualization summarises and visualizes several of the most significant statements in the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change&amp;rsquo;s (IPCC) recent Fifth Assessment Report, (Working Group I summary for policymakers, the Physical Science Basis). In 2014, IPCC will publish summaries concerning societal impacts, mitigation and adaptation.
The statements and facts presented are derived from the IPCC summary for policymakers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kyoto Protocol Explained</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/kyoto-protocol-explained/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/kyoto-protocol-explained/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QRlnnJrD7wQ
An Easy Overview Of The Kyoto Protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The science of climate change</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/the-science-of-climate-change/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/the-science-of-climate-change/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yIk1ggfi9c0
Recording Length: 1 hour
Professor Paul Valdes, School of Geographical Sciences, University of Bristol http://www.bristol.ac.uk/science/cour...
Climate change is rarely out of the headlines yet there appears to be continued controversy over the science.
In this captivating lecture, Professor Paul Valdes of Bristol&amp;rsquo;s world-renowned Geographical Sciences department cuts through the popular misconceptions and the media hype and throws open the topic to ask what&amp;rsquo;s really happening to the planet, and what scientists and policy makers can do about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wood Energy, UK, wood fuel heating - Ashden Award winner</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/wood-energy-uk-wood-fuel-heating-ashden-award-winner/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/wood-energy-uk-wood-fuel-heating-ashden-award-winner/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V_QJhYpmYn4
Wood Energy is one of the UK&amp;rsquo;s leading wood-fuel heating businesses, providing over a third of the country&amp;rsquo;s total wood heat capacity and saving almost 12,000 tonnes of CO2 emissions a year through its boiler installations. Based in Devon, the company helped to set up the UK&amp;rsquo;s only accredited wood-fuel training course for the industry to help raise standards. It has also worked hard to ensure a reliable supply of fuel for the heating systems it installs, by supporting local wood-fuel supply businesses and pellet mills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Environment Day- Africa Sustainable Energy</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/world-environment-day-africa-sustainable-energy/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/world-environment-day-africa-sustainable-energy/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1-NhA2FCHrU
Uploaded on Jun 5, 2009 In Africa, UNDP, as an implementing partner of the Global Environment Facility (GEF), is getting people in remote areas onto the electrical grid by harnessing green sources of energy like hydropower and solar energy. In the Embu district of central Kenya, a high rate of rainfall combined with a large amount of runoff water from the snows of Mount Kenya made hydropower the obvious choice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>