<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Water Purification on Sustainable Community Development Hub</title>
    <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/water-purification/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Water Purification on Sustainable Community Development Hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/water-purification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>All Things Water Course II, Water Reclaim Systems</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/12/all-things-water-course-ii-water-reclaim-systems/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/12/all-things-water-course-ii-water-reclaim-systems/index.html/</guid>
      <description>Part 1 of 3 https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ffut3SxSaAs
Advance your industry knowledge and expertise with All Things Water video courses featuring water treatment processes, water sector innovations, environmental challenges and public policies impacting the water industry. In this three-part Blacoh University course, industry expert Mark Girgenti discusses the fundamentals of water reclamation systems, system design sizing and feasibility.
Part 2 of 3 https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=taKAAZ4gmao
Part 3 of 3 https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vQaynF3qFDg</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LIFE&#43; ENSAT (CAT) / Enhancement of Soil Aquifer Treatment</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/12/life-ensat-cat-enhancement-of-soil-aquifer-treatment/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/12/life-ensat-cat-enhancement-of-soil-aquifer-treatment/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://youtu.be/bMjzetuLu_0
Cetaqua Published on Nov 7, 2012 SUBSCRIBE 34 SUBSCRIBE SUBSCRIBED UNSUBSCRIBE The ENSAT Life+ project aims at enhancing and optimizing this technology, progressing from laboratory studies to a pilot field scale study (located at the recharge site of Sant Vicenç dels Horts, Barcelona). Results obtained and lessons learned will be able to be implemented to transfer sites in Europe to improve the operation of the trial and full scale Aquifer Recharge plants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soil aquifer treatment to improve PERC dry cleaning chemical contaminated groundwater</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/12/8791/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/12/8791/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V146EyQPDx0
soil aquifer treatment to improve contaminated groundwater, use of vegetable oil to remediate by converting PCE contaminant to Ethene.
PCE vapor detection from dry cleaning facility 9 vapor extraction wells used to document remediation effort
ohn Mittelhauser &amp;amp; Assoc. Published on Jun 26, 2017
A short animation showing how soil and groundwater contamination at a dry cleaner was remediated by St. John-Mittelhauser &amp;amp; Associates using soil vapor extraction and biological injections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zawadi Nikuze - Healing &amp; Rebuilding Our Communities in Democratic Republic Congo</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/09/zawadi-nikuze-healing-rebuilding-our-communities-in-democratic-republic-congo/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/09/zawadi-nikuze-healing-rebuilding-our-communities-in-democratic-republic-congo/index.html/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7eLfnzm5AgU http://www.aglifpt.org/publications/articles/hroc/pdf/HROCTrainingLeaders.pdf  via Friendly Water for the World Published on Nov 1, 2013
   Zawadi Nikuze, from Healing and Rebuilding Our Communities, works with rape survivors in The Democratic Republic of Congo. She was recently trained to build biosand water filters by Friendly Water for the World. She will train the rape survivors to make and market the filters as part of their healing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nulfiltration Technology from Isarel</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/nulfiltration-technology-from-isarel/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/nulfiltration-technology-from-isarel/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://youtu.be/l0LNPJ3vavk
Replacing a NUF&amp;rsquo;s Membrane PVC connector Published on Mar 14, 2017
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kSRuKqQJQcg
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ncu3HC1AIFk
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UtCDVLB3lTI
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HzbLRTYUAuU
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s7e2wsdvDW0
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JrP6ku8FK1s</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lead Contamination Beyond Flint- Drinking Water and Childrens Health</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/lead-contamination-beyond-flint-drinking-water-and-childrens-health/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/lead-contamination-beyond-flint-drinking-water-and-childrens-health/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dsba3JetBrM Published on Apr 21, 2017 On the whole, American drinking water is safe. However, more than a year after toxic lead levels forced a federal state of emergency in Flint, MI, 63 percent of Americans report that they worry a great deal about polluted drinking water. This statistic comes from a new Gallup poll indicating that water pollution ranks the highest of six environmental concerns among respondents. While pipes in Flint are expected to be replaced with the help of a $97 million settlement, there are other cities with histories of unsafe lead levels - or other toxins - in drinking water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from Bolivia - EWB-UMR Chapter</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/02/lessons-from-bolivia-ewb-umr-chapter/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/02/lessons-from-bolivia-ewb-umr-chapter/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bBOeeRPJ4XI
This past summer the University of Missouri-Rolla&amp;rsquo;s chapter of Engineers Without Borders traveled to two destinations in Bolivia to apply their engineering skills to local problems. The first destination was a small boarding school in the Amazon. There the problem consisted of finding a clean source of water. The second location was in Inca Katurapi, a small village in the Andes where there had never been latrines. UMR students and faculty developed composting latrines for the community in an attempt to help reduce the infant mortality rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Water Quality Testing</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/introduction-to-water-quality-testing/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/introduction-to-water-quality-testing/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h3DvCCifdr0
Uploaded on Jun 13, 2010 Introduction to Water Quality Testing - Southern Regional Aquaculture Center - Product 331 - Aims to provide some of the knowledge of water quality which is essential to pond owners and aquaculturists. The work reported in this publication was supported in part by the Southern Regional Aquaculture Center through Grant No. 2006 38500 16977 from the U.S. Department of Agriculture, Cooperative State Research, Education, and Extension Service (CSREES)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemelson-MIT InvenTeams- Portable Water Treatment for Mexico</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/lemelson-mit-inventeams-portable-water-treatment-for-mexico/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/lemelson-mit-inventeams-portable-water-treatment-for-mexico/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nBN4hYJLY_o
2006 Nerinx Hall HS InvenTeam (Webster Groves, MO) demonstrate their invention: a portable water treatment device for a rural Mexican village.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ngelenge- The Tanzania Project (Engineers Without Borders)</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/ngelenge-the-tanzania-project-engineers-without-borders/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/ngelenge-the-tanzania-project-engineers-without-borders/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jSh2DLrgvDw
A documentary about Engineers Without Borders&amp;rsquo; work in Ngelenge, Tanzania.
ref:
Jason Shankel3 years ago Check out Engineers Without Borders. There are student and professional chapters all over the US. As for projects, need isn&amp;rsquo;t the only criterion. We seek out communities that are committed to local development. In this case, Ngelenge identified their needs and their preferred solutions and we provided expertise and some financial assistance. Helping people with their own ideas always works better than just providing them with aid.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>