<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Locally Maintainable Technology on Sustainable Community Development Hub</title>
    <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/locally-maintainable-technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Locally Maintainable Technology on Sustainable Community Development Hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/locally-maintainable-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Foldscope- A Paper Microscope that Costs $1</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2018/04/9265/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2018/04/9265/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qf-D1Upn-KU
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vQJDV4GE4aY
The Foldscope: A Paper Microscope that Costs $1
The New Yorker Published on Dec 14, 2015 Manu Prakash, a biophysicist at Stanford and the creator of the Foldscope, muses on the beauty of the microscopic world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SCD Hub path toward bringing a helpful chatbot to life</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/10/chatbot-tool/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/10/chatbot-tool/index.html/</guid>
      <description>SCD Hub is currently testing a chat service running with Hubot integrated as a chatroom attendant. Participants in our community clinics are invited to use this private service, as we work to make it more secure and future ready.
We would like you to consider how a good tool might be used to help organize SCD Hub Community Clinic participants. We envision ongoing support of teams connected to different community development efforts through automated checkins, scheduled delivery of printed and electronic training materials, &amp;lsquo;Clinic Companion&amp;rsquo; app to help keep projects and dialogues moving forward, while providing a central point where project documents and meeting notes can be reviewed, shared and maintained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kombucha Social Venture Health Beverage Company Community Success Prototype</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/08/kombucha-social-venture-health-beverage-company-community-success-prototype/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/08/kombucha-social-venture-health-beverage-company-community-success-prototype/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tBYqLQFNox8
Watch and learn about how House Kombucha started with a sustainable business model making kombucha locally while being kind to the planet with proprietor Rana Chang.
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hNnkayYyHP4
Kombucha Brooklyn Published on Aug 2, 2013
Kombucha is brewed in open-air vessels covered tightly with fine-weave cloth. Use culinary-grade ceramic, glass or stainless steel to ensure your &amp;lsquo;buch will be the healthiest &amp;lsquo;buch on your block. Here are some of our favorite vessels for fermenting &amp;lsquo;buch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pump Aid and the Elephant Toilet</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/07/pump-aid-and-the-elephant-toilet/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/07/pump-aid-and-the-elephant-toilet/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m1n3O3TEZ0k
Ethical Goods Published on Jun 12, 2008 SUBSCRIBE 1 A short video on the Elephant Toilet, Pump Aid&amp;rsquo;s award-winning solution to the global sanitation crisis. See www.pumpaid.org for more information Category Nonprofits &amp;amp; Activism</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make a shave horse from 2 by 4s</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/how-to-make-a-shave-horse-from-2-by-4s/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/how-to-make-a-shave-horse-from-2-by-4s/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=smGWNVSJTME
The shavehorse is commonly used as the preparation of stock prior to turning in a lathe, to roughly form cylindrical billets, the intermediate dressing phase between a crudely dressed raw split log and the final lathe work.
As the name &amp;ldquo;horse&amp;rdquo; suggests, the worker sits astride the shaving horse. The clamp is operated by the operator pressing their feet onto a treadle bar below. A foot-actuated clamp holds the work piece securely against pulling forces, especially as when shaped with a drawknife or spokeshave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Studio 3.0 Canary 1</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/android-studio-3-0-canary-1/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/android-studio-3-0-canary-1/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rHiA66zUv8c&amp;amp;list=PLWz5rJ2EKKc_w6fodMGrA1_tsI3pqPbqa
This video shows many of the important and useful features common in IDEs or Integrated Development Environment. IntelliJ IDE provides the core features of the Android Studio distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowered Transform Used Tires Into Shoes At Detroit Treads</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/05/unemployed-transform-used-tires-into-shoes-at-detroit-treads/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/05/unemployed-transform-used-tires-into-shoes-at-detroit-treads/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ogTFJf4mfs4
Unemployed Transform Used Tires Into Shoes At Detroit Treads
Detroit Treads is employing people who likely wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to get other jobs transforming used car tires into shoes being sold all over the world. The flip flops sport an Olde English style D on the sole. This feature is part of CBS 62&amp;rsquo;s Eye On Detroit series as seen weekdays during &amp;ldquo;CBS This Morning&amp;rdquo;. For more visit http://cbsdetroit.com/eyeondetroit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>