<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Insulation on Sustainable Community Development Hub</title>
    <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/insulation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Insulation on Sustainable Community Development Hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/insulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cumbria Energy Efficiency Advice Centre,UK - Ashden Award winner</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/cumbria-energy-efficiency-advice-centreuk-ashden-award-winner/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/cumbria-energy-efficiency-advice-centreuk-ashden-award-winner/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=su1NWjH6fcg
Cumbria Energy Efficiency Advice Centre is scaling up simple energy efficiency measures throughout Cumbria with an integrated and highly professional service offering advice, funding and insulation. In just two years it has insulated the cavity walls of over 9,000 homes and provided loft insulation for over 5,000 homes, saving 12,500 tonnes of CO2 a year and reducing fuel bills by over £1.6 million a year. CEEAC helps local people who are faced with a bewildering array of grants to make sense of the options and access the right funds for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussing insluation on off grid construction and smallcabins</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/discussing-insluation-on-off-grid-construction-and-small-cabins/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/discussing-insluation-on-off-grid-construction-and-small-cabins/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zN1Os9T-S6I
Published on Nov 9, 2013 Discussing and showing insulation options for remote and off grid construction projects, which will usually involve small cabins and alternative construction methods. Insulation choices need to take these factors into consideration: The construction project may be located in an area without utilities The place may go for long periods without being temperature controlled The place may suffer environmental damage that goes unnoticed for a long period of time The work crew may not be able to clean clothes and or shower regularly and may be camping on site rather than going home to full utilities at the end of the work day.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>