<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Health on Sustainable Community Development Hub</title>
    <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health on Sustainable Community Development Hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Left the Hospital System and Started Working in Telemedicine</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/09/why-i-left-the-hospital-system-and-started-working-in-telemedicine/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/09/why-i-left-the-hospital-system-and-started-working-in-telemedicine/index.html/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
Behind one woman&amp;rsquo;s decision to pursue a medical career at a San Francisco Internet startup.
This video appeared in the story This App Will Be a Game-Changer for Getting Birth Control without the ACA
https://app.nurx.com/
&amp;ldquo;The company is currently only authorized to deliver in California, Washington, New York, Washington, D.C., Illinois, Virginia, and Pennsylvania. But it&amp;rsquo;s growing quickly-next up will be Massachusetts, Florida, Michigan, Missouri, Minnesota, and Maryland.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City Repair Portland</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/09/city-repair-portland/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/09/city-repair-portland/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=7&amp;amp;v=uxDIgm14DLc  Respectful Revolution Published on Mar 28, 2017
  Mark Lakeman is a famous architect in Portland, OR. Why? After traveling around the world and seeing many cities from different cultures, Mark realized that one thing was missing from American cities: squares and plazas. Americans don&amp;rsquo;t connect on the streets because there&amp;rsquo;s no place to do so. Streets are designed for motorized traffic. Intersections aren&amp;rsquo;t made to hang out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultuer- Music - Ethiopian (Music by Gigi Shibabaw-Washintu)</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/07/nuclear-testing-footage-music-by-gigi-shibabaw-washintu/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/07/nuclear-testing-footage-music-by-gigi-shibabaw-washintu/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qcdQJ7OoJN4&amp;amp;list=RDqvKKkhqGGww&amp;amp;index=10
&amp;nbsp;
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uKGGV5WcZdY&amp;amp;list=RDqvKKkhqGGww&amp;amp;index=6
Kehlog Albran Published on Sep 10, 2008
This is a clip from the documentary film &amp;ldquo;Trinity And Beyond The Atomic Bomb Movie&amp;rdquo; narrated by William Shatner. I replaced the soundtrack with the song &amp;ldquo;Washintu&amp;rdquo; by Ethiopian singer Gigi. Her hypnotic sound blends well with the footage.
Trinity and Beyond: The Atomic Bomb Movie is a 1995 American documentary film directed by Peter Kuran and narrated by William Shatner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the crisis of disconnection</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/addiction-as-a-symptom-of-the-crisis-of-disconnection/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/addiction-as-a-symptom-of-the-crisis-of-disconnection/index.html/</guid>
      <description>Published on Oct 29, 2015
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ao8L-0nSYzg
As a part of SCD Hub&amp;rsquo;s ongoing work collecting important &amp;lsquo;soft skills&amp;rsquo; videos and resources, we take a look at addiction as a human rights issue. Johann Hari&amp;rsquo;s important work helps us understand addiction as a symptom of social isolation. If as he states, &amp;ldquo;the opposite of addiction is not sobriety, the opposite of addiction is connection&amp;rdquo;, then sustainable community development is the only way to really address the modern crisis of opiate, alcohol and sugar addiction in modern society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harvard Public Health- The Minnesota measles outbreak</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/harvard-public-health-the-minnesota-measles-outbreak/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/harvard-public-health-the-minnesota-measles-outbreak/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://soundcloud.com/harvardpublichealth/june-1-2017-the-minnesota-measles-outbreak?in=harvardpublichealth/sets/harvard-chan-this-week-in
June 1, 2017 - Health officials in Minnesota are now grappling with that state&amp;rsquo;s largest measles outbreak in several decades. As of May 31, the Minnesota Department of Health had confirmed 70 cases of the disease. The outbreak is being blamed in part on anti-vaccine groups who targeted Somali-Americans, leading to a sharp drop in the number of children receiving the measles, mumps, and rubella (MMR) vaccine. In this week&amp;rsquo;s podcast, we get perspective on the outbreak from childhood vaccine expert Marie McCormick, Sumner and Esther Feldberg Professor of Maternal and Child Health, at Harvard T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lead Contamination Beyond Flint- Drinking Water and Childrens Health</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/lead-contamination-beyond-flint-drinking-water-and-childrens-health/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/lead-contamination-beyond-flint-drinking-water-and-childrens-health/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dsba3JetBrM Published on Apr 21, 2017 On the whole, American drinking water is safe. However, more than a year after toxic lead levels forced a federal state of emergency in Flint, MI, 63 percent of Americans report that they worry a great deal about polluted drinking water. This statistic comes from a new Gallup poll indicating that water pollution ranks the highest of six environmental concerns among respondents. While pipes in Flint are expected to be replaced with the help of a $97 million settlement, there are other cities with histories of unsafe lead levels - or other toxins - in drinking water.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>