<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Industrial Ecology on Sustainable Community Development Hub</title>
    <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/industrial-ecology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Industrial Ecology on Sustainable Community Development Hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/industrial-ecology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Soil aquifer treatment to improve PERC dry cleaning chemical contaminated groundwater</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/12/8791/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/12/8791/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V146EyQPDx0
soil aquifer treatment to improve contaminated groundwater, use of vegetable oil to remediate by converting PCE contaminant to Ethene.
PCE vapor detection from dry cleaning facility 9 vapor extraction wells used to document remediation effort
ohn Mittelhauser &amp;amp; Assoc. Published on Jun 26, 2017
A short animation showing how soil and groundwater contamination at a dry cleaner was remediated by St. John-Mittelhauser &amp;amp; Associates using soil vapor extraction and biological injections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dyed without waste - developing a process to save water in the textile industry</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/12/dyed-without-waste-developing-a-process-to-save-water-in-the-textile-industry/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/12/dyed-without-waste-developing-a-process-to-save-water-in-the-textile-industry/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.euronews.com/2017/03/20/dyed-without-waste-developing-a-process-to-save-water-in-the-textile-industry
&amp;nbsp;
&amp;rdquo; factory says it consumes an average of some 350 million litres of water every year. &amp;hellip;80 litres of water per kilo of fabric&amp;rdquo;
&amp;nbsp;
&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;to recycle water from textile dyeing in efficient, affordable ways. &amp;hellip;test recycling unit.
to clean up the water.:
A first process, called electro-coagulation, eliminates colorants.
A second, called reverse osmosis, contributes to the elimination of salts.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Brewed Power Walls</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/09/diy-18650-cell-power-wall/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/09/diy-18650-cell-power-wall/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Nsw8PhDlhSg
This project is now at 40kwh of storage with fully configurable BMS from http://www.batrium.com. See it with upgraded safety and planning https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list&amp;hellip; ▶▶
The process continues building my Powerwall bigger and better Balancing the pack before installing it before I have a little issue with pixies escaping making some magic white smoke. I have to break off all the little plastic clips so it sits on the mount much better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ENWORKS, UK, Energy efficiency advice for businesses - Ashden Award winner</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/enworks-uk-energy-efficiency-advice-for-businesses-ashden-award-winner/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/enworks-uk-energy-efficiency-advice-for-businesses-ashden-award-winner/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S3oZjh5wcE8
This video can be downloaded here: http://www.ashdenawards.org/winners/enworks ENWORKS won an Ashden Award for Sustainable Energy in 2007.
http://enworksinabox.com/sites/default/files/EREiKS%20Evaluation%20FR.pdf
ENWORKS based in Greater Manchester is helping businesses in the North-West reduce their use of resources, cut their waste production &amp;ndash; and make huge cost savings. Almost 1,000 businesses are participating in the programme, saving them about £12 million a year from a total capital investment of only £5.5 million. The ENWORKS scheme is reducing CO2 emissions by an impressive 18,000 tonnes a year.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>