<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Water Conservation on Sustainable Community Development Hub</title>
    <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/water-conservation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Water Conservation on Sustainable Community Development Hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/water-conservation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix a Running Toilet - 3 Most Common Problems</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/12/how-to-fix-a-running-toilet-3-most-common-problems/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/12/how-to-fix-a-running-toilet-3-most-common-problems/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XzfRd9immBo
House In Progress Published on Mar 2, 2017 SUBSCRIBE 2.8K SUBSCRIBE SUBSCRIBED UNSUBSCRIBE Universal Toilet Flapper 3&amp;rdquo;: http://amzn.to/2mj5CpK Universal Toilet Flapper 2&amp;rdquo;: http://amzn.to/2mG44ci Fill Valve and Flapper Kit: http://amzn.to/2neEmYK High Performance Fill Valve: http://amzn.to/2lYSBjl
Running toilet? Leaking toilet? Nobody likes a toilet that keeps running. We will show you the three most common causes and how to fix a running toilet so that you can avoid this expensive problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I110 Biomimicry and the creation in plants</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/i110-biomimicry-and-the-creation-in-plants/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/i110-biomimicry-and-the-creation-in-plants/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fH099OPYK4s
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sf4oW8OtaPY
Published on Sep 11, 2015 - Biomimicry, the practice of looking deeply into nature for solutions to engineering, design and other challenges, has inspired a film about it&amp;rsquo;s ground-breaking vision for creating a long-term, sustainable world. This film covers how mimicking nature solves some of our most pressing problems, from reducing carbon emissions to saving water. The film, titled &amp;ldquo;Biomimicry&amp;rdquo; features Janine Benyus, is brought to you by Leonardo DiCaprio, Executive Producers Oliver Stanton, directed by Leila Conners, produced by Mathew Schmid and Bryony Schwan, created by Tree Media with Executive Producers Roee Sharon Peled and George DiCaprio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patagonia Distribution Center Built Green With LEED</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/patagonia-distribution-center-built-green-with-leed-2/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/patagonia-distribution-center-built-green-with-leed-2/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-3KPlk34DZ0
Published on Aug 31, 2007 When we needed to expand our distribution center in Reno, Nevada we looked to the Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design, or LEED, certification standards as our guide to building a green building that balances environmental responsibility, resource efficiency and the comfort and well-being of our workforce. The Patagonia Footprint Chronicles allows you to track the environmental impact of a specific Patagonia product from design through delivery.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>