<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sustainable Economics on Sustainable Community Development Hub</title>
    <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/sustainable-economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sustainable Economics on Sustainable Community Development Hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/sustainable-economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kombucha Social Venture Health Beverage Company Community Success Prototype</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/08/kombucha-social-venture-health-beverage-company-community-success-prototype/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/08/kombucha-social-venture-health-beverage-company-community-success-prototype/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tBYqLQFNox8
Watch and learn about how House Kombucha started with a sustainable business model making kombucha locally while being kind to the planet with proprietor Rana Chang.
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hNnkayYyHP4
Kombucha Brooklyn Published on Aug 2, 2013
Kombucha is brewed in open-air vessels covered tightly with fine-weave cloth. Use culinary-grade ceramic, glass or stainless steel to ensure your &amp;lsquo;buch will be the healthiest &amp;lsquo;buch on your block. Here are some of our favorite vessels for fermenting &amp;lsquo;buch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Satisficing- when the optimal solution cannot be determined</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/satisficing/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/satisficing/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2M2I2ka4rXU
via https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Satisficing
Satisficing is a decision-making strategy or cognitive heuristic that entails searching through the available alternatives until an acceptability threshold is met.[1] The term satisficing, a combination of satisfy and suffice,[2] was introduced by Herbert A. Simon in 1956,[3] although the concept was first posited in his 1947 book Administrative Behavior.[4][5] Simon used satisficing to explain the behavior of decision makers under circumstances in which an optimal solution cannot be determined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ithaca Hours- Local Currency</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/ithaca-hours-local-currency/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/ithaca-hours-local-currency/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Jy2nCHX36tI **Uploaded on Aug 15, 2010  **Grassroots Activist Guild ithacahours.org Ithaca Hours is a local currency system that promotes local economic strength and community self-reliance in ways which will support economic and social justice, ecology, community participation and human aspirations in and around Ithaca, New York.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qualifying a Project Consultant</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/qualifying-a-consultant/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/06/qualifying-a-consultant/index.html/</guid>
      <description>I recently spoke with the woman responsible for the years of successful operations at Ares Thrift Store in Boulder. I asked her what the concept of &amp;lsquo;Sustainable Community Development&amp;rsquo; meant to her; if she had anything to suggest anything for the SCD Hub video library. She explained that one of the biggest challenges was to vet the abilities of people who she had hired in the past for web design, graphic, print media design, various other tech duties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowered Transform Used Tires Into Shoes At Detroit Treads</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/05/unemployed-transform-used-tires-into-shoes-at-detroit-treads/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2017/05/unemployed-transform-used-tires-into-shoes-at-detroit-treads/index.html/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ogTFJf4mfs4
Unemployed Transform Used Tires Into Shoes At Detroit Treads
Detroit Treads is employing people who likely wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to get other jobs transforming used car tires into shoes being sold all over the world. The flip flops sport an Olde English style D on the sole. This feature is part of CBS 62&amp;rsquo;s Eye On Detroit series as seen weekdays during &amp;ldquo;CBS This Morning&amp;rdquo;. For more visit http://cbsdetroit.com/eyeondetroit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>-Financial reform for a sustainable economy-- Part 2- Michael Kumhof</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/financial-reform-for-a-sustainable-economy-part-2-michael-kumhof/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/financial-reform-for-a-sustainable-economy-part-2-michael-kumhof/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YnAtHbDptj8
Published on Jan 30, 2013 &amp;ldquo;Financial reform for a sustainable economy&amp;rdquo; is a seminar hosted by Swedish think tank Global Utmaning (Global Challenge) with keynote speaker Michael Kumhof, International Monetary Fund (IMF) and Bernard Lietaer, international expert on monetary systems and the author of the book &amp;ldquo;Money the missing link in sustainability&amp;rdquo;. Michael Kumhof discussed the Chicago Plan and how to create a sustainable economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tale of Two Sewing Machines</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/a-tale-of-two-sewing-machines/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/a-tale-of-two-sewing-machines/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j6JNmBzXBC0
Uploaded on Mar 19, 2009 What happens when American and Australian women friends buy two manual sewing machines for Congolese women in a remote village?
This short video documents the impact of a gift of two sewing machines to women in an isolated village in the Democratic Republic of Congo.
Journey with the friends up the Congo River and its tributaries to see the results of their gift: From two manual sewing machines: income-generation; maternal health initiatives; nutrition garden; malaria prevention&amp;hellip; and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Next Industrial Revolution Trailer</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/the-next-industrial-revolution-trailer/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/the-next-industrial-revolution-trailer/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MoO_DwW4nDs
Uploaded on Aug 5, 2008 THE NEXT INDUSTRIAL REVOLUTION is a new 55 minute film, produced by Earthome Productions to communicate the work and vision of architect William McDonough and chemist Dr. Michael Braungart, two leaders in a growing movement to transform the relationship between commerce and nature.
McDonough and Braungart work with corporations with over half a trillion dollars in annual sales, companies like Ford and Nike, to redesign buildings, processes, and products to work according to nature&amp;rsquo;s rules.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>