<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tanzania on Sustainable Community Development Hub</title>
    <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/tanzania/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tanzania on Sustainable Community Development Hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://scdhub.netlify.com/cat/tanzania/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ngelenge- The Tanzania Project (Engineers Without Borders)</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/ngelenge-the-tanzania-project-engineers-without-borders/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/ngelenge-the-tanzania-project-engineers-without-borders/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jSh2DLrgvDw
A documentary about Engineers Without Borders&amp;rsquo; work in Ngelenge, Tanzania.
ref:
Jason Shankel3 years ago Check out Engineers Without Borders. There are student and professional chapters all over the US. As for projects, need isn&amp;rsquo;t the only criterion. We seek out communities that are committed to local development. In this case, Ngelenge identified their needs and their preferred solutions and we provided expertise and some financial assistance. Helping people with their own ideas always works better than just providing them with aid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zara Solar Ltd, Tanzania, Affordable rural solar pv energy - Ashden Award winner</title>
      <link>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/zara-solar-ltd-tanzania-affordable-rural-solar-pv-energy-ashden-award-winner/index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scdhub.netlify.com/videos/2014/01/zara-solar-ltd-tanzania-affordable-rural-solar-pv-energy-ashden-award-winner/index.html/</guid>
      <description>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SHgXR2cmVyA
Uploaded on Feb 26, 2008 This video can be downloaded here: http://www.ashdenawards.org/winners/zara Zara Solar won an Ashden Award for Sustainable Energy in 2007.
You can follow us on: Facebook http://bit.ly/9GKbIM Twitter http://twitter.com/AshdenAwards Blog: http://www.ashdenawards.org/blog/latest
To find out more visit the link above and check out the Ashden Awards Blog http://ashdenawards.blogspot.com
Zara Solar Ltd. is the leading provider of solar PV in Northern Tanzania. Given that only 10% of the whole population and 2% of the rural population have access to the electricity grid in Tanzania, solar energy would seem to be an obvious alternative.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>